In the previous video, we gave the
mathematical definition of the cost
在以前的视频，我们给了代价函数的数学定义
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
function. In this video, let's look at
some examples, to get back to intuition
在这段视频中，让我们来看看一些例子，在直觉上理解下
about what the cost function is doing, and
why we want to use it. To recap, here's
代价函数是用来做什么的，和为什么我们要使用它。总括来说
what we had last time. We want to fit a
straight line to our data, so we had this
这是我们上节课学到的 我们希望找到与数据拟合的直线
formed as a hypothesis with these
parameters theta zero and theta one, and
所以 根据这些参数θ0和θ1形成为一个假设
with different choices of the parameters
we end up with different straight line
随着选择不同的参数，我们得到不同的直线
fits. So the data which are fit
like so, and there's a cost function, and
就会有像这样的数据对应 这存在一个代价函数
that was our optimization objective.
[sound] So this video, in order to better
这是我们的优化目标 所以这段视频中，为了更好地
visualize the cost function J, I'm going
to work with a simplified hypothesis
可视化代价函数J，我要使用一个简化的假设函数
function, like that shown on the right. So
I'm gonna use my simplified hypothesis,
如显示在右侧的那个 所以 我会用我的简化假设
which is just theta one times X. We can,
if you want, think of this as setting the
这个假设仅包含这些参数θ1*x，如果你愿意，你可以认为这是设置
parameter theta zero equal to 0. So I
have only one parameter theta one and
参数θ0=0 于是，我只有一个参数θ1
my cost function is similar to before
except that now H of X that is now equal
我的代价函数和以前差不太多 只不过 h(x)现在直接等于
to just theta one times X. And I have only
one parameter theta one and so my
θ1乘x 我只有θ1一个参数了，所以我们的
optimization objective is to minimize j of
theta one. In pictures what this means is
优化目标是尽量减少J(θ1) 在图片中，意思就是
that if theta zero equals zero that
corresponds to choosing only hypothesis
如果θ0=0，相当于只选择经过远点的假设函数
functions that pass through the origin,
that pass through the point (0, 0). Using
也就是通过点(0,0)
this simplified definition of a hypothesizing cost
function let's try to understand the cost
应用这个假设代价函数的简化定义，让我们去更好的了解
function concept better. It turns out that
two key functions we want to understand.
代价函数概念 这里有两个关键函数我们想要了解
The first is the hypothesis function, and
the second is a cost function. So, notice
第一个是假设函数 第二个是代价函数
that the hypothesis, right, H of X. For a
face value of theta one, this is a
注意一下这个假设函数h(x)，是的，系数为θ1，这是一个关于x的函数
function of X. So the hypothesis is a
function of, what is the size of the house
因此这个函数是一个函数实现房子x的尺寸的判定
X. In contrast, the cost function, J,
that's a function of the parameter, theta
与此相反，代价函数J的参数是θ1
one, which controls the slope of the
straight line. Let's plot these functions
它控制该直线的斜率。让我们来绘制这些函数
and try to understand them both better.
Let's start with the hypothesis. On the left,
并试着去更好的了解他们 让我们以假设函数开始 在左边
let's say here's my training set with
three points at (1, 1), (2, 2), and (3, 3). Let's
这里是我的训练集有三个点(1,1)，(2,2)，(3,3)
pick a value theta one, so when theta one
equals one, and if that's my choice for
让我们选个θ1的值 所以当θ1=1，如果这是我的选择
theta one, then my hypothesis is going to
look like this straight line over here.
那么我的假设就是在这里的这条直线。
And I'm gonna point out, when I'm plotting
my hypothesis function. X-axis, my
我会指出，当我绘制我的假设函数。 X轴，我的横轴
horizontal axis is labeled X, is labeled
you know, size of the house over here.
横轴标记为X，标记你知道的，在这里的房子的大小。
Now, of temporary, set
theta one equals one, what I want to do is
现在，暂时的，θ1=1，我想要弄清楚的是
figure out what is j of theta one, when
theta one equals one. So let's go ahead
当θ1=1时，J(θ1)的值 所以，让我们继续前进
and compute what the cost function has
for. You'll devalue one. Well, as usual,
计算出代价函数 你会降低它的价值 嗯，像往常一样
my cost function is defined as follows,
right? Some from, some of 'em are training
我的代价函数定义如下，对不对？一些训练集
sets of this usual squared error term.
And, this is therefore equal to. And this.
误差项平方的和 这因此 等于 而这个
Of theta one x I minus y I and if you
simplify this turns out to be. That. Zero
θ1*x(i)-y(i)，如果你简化这个会得到
Squared to zero squared to zero squared which
is of course, just equal to zero. Now,
平方值为0 平方为0 平方 这是当然的就等于零
inside the cost function. It turns out each
of these terms here is equal to zero. Because
在代价函数中，事实上，这些在这里是等于零
for the specific training set I have or my
3 training examples are (1, 1), (2, 2), (3,3). If theta
对于特定的训练集 我有我的3个训练样例(1,1)，(2,2)，(3,3)
one is equal to one. Then h of x. H of x
i. Is equal to y I exactly, let me write
如果θ1=1 那么h( x(i) )=y(i) 让我写的更清楚一点，好吗
this better. Right? And so, h of x minus
y, each of these terms is equal to zero,
所有的h(x)-y结果都是0
which is why I find that j of one is equal
to zero. So, we now know that j of one Is
也就是J(1)=0 所以，我们现在知道J(1)=0
equal to zero. Let's plot that. What I'm
gonna do on the right is plot my cost
让我描绘出它 我在右侧画出我的代价函数
function j. And notice, because my cost
function is a function of my parameter
注意，因为我的代价函数的参数是θ1
theta one, when I plot my cost function,
the horizontal axis is now labeled with
当我绘制我的代价函数，横轴是现在标为θ1
theta one. So I have j of one zero
zero so let's go ahead and plot that. End
所以，我们现在有J(1)=0让我们继续描绘
up with. An X over there. Now lets look at
some other examples. Theta-1 can take on a
那边的X  现在，让我们看看其他一些例子。 θ1可以采取
range of different values. Right? So
theta-1 can take on the negative values,
一个范围内的不同值，对吗？因此，θ1可以取负数
zero, positive values. So what if theta-1
is equal to 0.5. What happens then? Let's
0，正数 那么，如果θ1=0.5会发生什么？让我们
go ahead and plot that. I'm now going to
set theta-1 equals 0.5, and in that case my
继续前进，绘制 我现在要设置θ1=0.5，在这种情况下
hypothesis now looks like this. As a line
with slope equals to 0.5, and, lets
假设现在看起来是这样。为一条斜率等于0.5的直线
compute J, of 0.5. So that is going to be
one over 2M of, my usual cost function.
我们计算J(0.5) 所以这将是我平常代价函数的是1/2M
It turns out that the cost function is
going to be the sum of square values of
事实证明，代价函数是这些线的长度的平方值的总和
the height of this line. Plus the sum of
square of the height of that line, plus
把这些线的长度的平方相加
the sum of square of the height of that
line, right? ?Cause just this vertical
这些线的高度的平方的总和，对不对？是垂直距离
distance, that's the difference between,
you know, Y. I. and the predicted value, H
也就是 你知道的，y与预测值间的距离
of XI, right? So the first example
is going to be 0.5 minus one squared.
预测值是h( x(i) )，对不对？因此，第一个例子将是(0.5-1)的平方
Because my hypothesis predicted 0.5.
Whereas, the actual value was one. For my
因为我的假设值是0.5 然而，实际值是1
second example, I get, one minus two
squared, because my hypothesis predicted
第二个例子中，我得到(1-2)^2，因为我的假设值为1
one, but the actual housing price was two.
And then finally, plus. 1.5 minus three
但实际的住房价格是2。最后再加上(1.5-3)的平方
squared. And so that's equal to one over
two times three. Because, M when trading
所以等于1/(2*3) 因为M有3组例子
set size, right, have three training
examples. In that, that's times
在那，化简为
simplifying for the parentheses it's 3.5.
So that's 3.5 over six which is about
(3.5)  因此 结果为3.5/6 约定于0.68
0.68. So now we know that j of 0.5 is
about 0.68. Lets go and plot that. Oh
所以，现在我们知道，J(0.5)约等于0.68。让我们去绘制它
excuse me, math error, it's actually 0.58. So
we plot that which is maybe about over
对不起，数学错误，它实际上是0.58。因此，我们把它绘制在这里
there. Okay? Now, let's do one more. How
about if theta one is equal to zero, what
好吗？现在，让我们再做一个 当θ1=0会如何呢
is J of zero equal to? It turns out that
if theta one is equal to zero, then H of X
事实证明，如果θ1=0，则h(x)
is just equal to, you know, this flat
line, right, that just goes horizontally
恰好等于 一条水平线，没错，平行
like this. And so, measuring the errors.
We have that J of zero is equal to one
像这样 所以计算误差。我们有J(0)
over two M, times one squared plus two
squared plus three squared, which is, One
=1/2M ( 1^2 + 2^2 + 3^2 ) = 1/6*14约等于2.3
six times fourteen which is about 2.3. So
let's go ahead and plot as well. So it
所以，让我们继续前进，并绘制好。因此
ends up with a value around 2.3
and of course we can keep on doing this
得到与2.3左右的值，当然，我们可以继续这样做
for other values of theta one. It turns
out that you can have you know negative
为θ1赋上其他值 事实证明，你也可以给θ1赋值负数
values of theta one as well so if theta
one is negative then h of x would be equal
如果θ1是负数 比如h(x)将等于
to say minus 0.5 times x then theta
one is minus 0.5 and so that corresponds
-0.5x 当θ1=-0.5
to a hypothesis with a
slope of negative 0.5. And you can
对应的假设函数是斜率为-0.5的直线
actually keep on computing these errors.
This turns out to be, you know, for 0.5,
我们可以继续计算这些误差 你知道，当这个值为0.5，
it turns out to have really high error. It
works out to be something, like, 5.25. And
就会有非常高的误差 最后得到的数是，5.25
so on, and the different values of theta
one, you can compute these things, right?
继续，随着θ1的值不同，你可以计算出这些东西，对不对？
And it turns out that you, your computed
range of values, you get something like
而事实证明，你在一定范围计算一些值，你会得到这样的东西
that. And by computing the range of
values, you can actually slowly create
计算的值的范围，你可以慢慢地创建
out. What does function J of Theta say and
that's what J of Theta is. To recap, for
函数J(θ1)到底是什么 总的来说
each value of theta one, right? Each value
of theta one corresponds to a different
对于每个θ1的值 都对应着假设函数的一个值
hypothesis, or to a different straight
line fit on the left. And for each value
或对应着一条不同的直线，如左侧 并且每个值
of theta one, we could then derive a
different value of j of theta one. And for
θ1 我们可以得出一个不同的J(θ1)的值
example, you know, theta one=1,
corresponded to this straight line
例如，您知道，θ1= 1，符合这条直线
straight through the data. Whereas theta
one=0.5. And this point shown in magenta
正好经过数据  然而当θ1= 0.5 对应的可能就是红色画出的这条线
corresponded to maybe that line, and theta
one=zero which is shown in blue that corresponds to
当θ1=0对应的是蓝色画出的水平线
this horizontal line. Right, so for each
value of theta one we wound up with a
对，所以我们每个值θ1都对应J(θ1)一个值
different value of J of theta one and we
could then use this to trace out this plot
然后，我们可以使用这个可以在右侧描绘出这个图形
on the right. Now you remember, the
optimization objective for our learning
现在，你还记得在我们学习算法时的优化目标
algorithm is we want to choose the value
of theta one. That minimizes J of theta one.
是我们通过选择θ1的价值 最大限度地减少J(θ1)
Right? This was our objective function for
the linear regression. Well, looking at
这是我们的线性回归的目标函数的
this curve, the value that minimizes j of
theta one is, you know, theta one equals
这条曲线中 使J(θ1)最小的值是1，你知道 当θ1=1
to one. And low and behold, that is indeed
the best possible straight line fit
看呀，这确实是能最好的拟合数据的直线
through our data, by setting theta one
equals one. And just, for this particular
通过设置θ1=1 这只是以个特殊的训练集
training set, we actually end up fitting
it perfectly. And that's why minimizing j
我们实际上已经完美的满足了它 这就是为什么要
of theta one corresponds to finding a
straight line that fits the data well. So,
通使J(θ1)最小来找到一个最拟合数据的直线 因此
to wrap up. In this video, we looked up
some plots. To understand the cost
在这段视频中，我们看到了一些图形 要了解代价函数
function. To do so, we simplify the
algorithm. So that it only had one
要做到这一点，我们简化了算法，使它只能有一个参数θ1
parameter theta one. And we set the
parameter theta zero to be only zero. In the next video.
我们设置参数θ0=0 在接下来的视频
We'll go back to the original problem
formulation and look at some
我们会回到原来的问题的公式
visualizations involving both theta zero
and theta one. That is without setting theta
看一些涉及到θ0和θ1的图 这是没有设置θ0=0
zero to zero. And hopefully that will give
you, an even better sense of what the cost
希望这会让你在代价函数J是如何
function j is doing in the original
linear regression formulation.
在最初的线性回归公式中工作的有更好地理解